现在我们知道MAC是什么了，我们继续构建第一类安全的MAC
Now that we know what MACs are, let's go
ahead and build our first secure MACs.
First I want to remind you that a MAC is a
pair of algorithms. The first is a signing
首先我想提醒大家，MAC是一对算法
algorithm that's given a message and a key
will generate a corresponding tag And the
第一个是签名算法，给定信息和密钥，会产生相应的标签
second is verification algorithms are
given a key message and a tag while
第二个是验证算法，给定密钥、信息和标签
outputs zero or one depending on whether
the tag is valid or not. And we said that
输出0或1，结果取决于标签是否有效
a MAC is secure if it is existentially
unforgeable under a chosen message attack.
我们说过MAC是安全的，如果它对选择信息攻击是不可被存在性伪造的
In other words, the attackers allow to
mount a chosen message attack where he can
换句话说，攻击者可以实施选择信息攻击
submit arbitrary messages of his choice
and obtain the corresponding tags for
他提交由他选择的任意信息，并获得相应的标签
those messages, and then despite the
ability to generate arbitrary tags The
然后尽管有能力生成任意的标签
attacker cannot create a new message-tag pair that was not given to him
攻击者也不能产生一个新的信息-标签对
不是选择信息攻击中所给出的信息-标签对，上一节中我们已经
during the chosen message attack. Okay so
we've already seen this definition in the
看了这个定义。现在的问题是我们如何构建MAC？
last segment and now the question is how
do we build secure MACs? So the first
我想给大家看的第一个例子是证明任何安全的PRF可直接
example I want to give you is basically
showing that any secure PRF directly gives
给我们一个安全的MAC。那我们看怎么来做
us a secure MAC as well. So let's see how
we do it. So suppose we have a pseudo
random function so the pseudo random
function takes and inputs X and outputs in
假设我们有一个伪随机函数PRF，这个PRF取输入X，输出Y
Y. And let's define the following MAC. So
the way we sign a message 'M' is basically
我们定义如下的MAC，我们为信息M签名
by simply evaluating the function at the
point 'M' So the tag for the message M is
即为计算函数在M处的值。所以信息M的标签
simply the value of the function at the
point M and then the way we verify a
就是在点M处的函数值，然后我们通过这一对来验证信息
message to that pair is by recomputing the
value of the function at the message M and
方法就是重新计算在信息M处的函数值
checking whether that is equal to the tag
given to us. We say yes if so and we
检查结果是否等于给我们的标签。如果一样，我们说“是”
reject otherwise. So here you have in
pictures basically that when Alice wants
否则我们拒绝。那么这里有图片描述
to send a message to Bob she computes a
tag by the value of PRF and then she
Alice想给Bob发一条消息，她计算标签通过计算PRF的值得来
appends this tag to the message, Bob
receives the corresponding tab pair, he
那么她把这个得来的标签附在信息后面，Bob收到了这一对信息
recomputes the value of the function and
tests whether the given tag is actually
他重新计算函数值，并测试得到的标签
equal to the value of the function at the
point M. So let's look at a bad example of
是否等于在点M处的函数值。那么我们看一个设计的不好的例子
this instruction. And so suppose that we
have a pseudo-random function that happens
那么假设我们有一个伪随机函数
to output only ten bits. Okay, so this is
a fine pseudo-random function and it just
只输出10位，好，这是一个很好的伪随机函数
so happens that for any message 'M' it
only outputs ten bits value. My question
对于任何信息M，它只输出10位
to you is if we use this function 'F' to
construct a MAC, is that going to be a
我的问题是，如果我们使用这个函数F构建了一个MAC
secure MAC? So the answer is no, this MAC
is insecure. In particular because the
得到的MAC是安全的吗？那么答案是否定的，这个MAC是不安全的。特别地
tags are too short. So consider the
following simple adversary. What the
是因为标签太短。那么考虑下面这个简单例子
adversary will do is simply choose an
arbitrary message M and just guess the
攻击者选择一个任意信息M
value of the MAC for that particular
message. Now, because the tag is only ten
随便猜一个MAC的值，作为这个信息的标签，由于这个标签只有10位
bits long, the adversary has a chance of
one in two to the ten in guessing the MAC
攻击者有1除以2的10次方的机会猜中MAC
correctly. In other words, the advantage
of the guessing adversary, one distinctly
换句话说，攻击者猜测的优势
guesses a random tag for a given message.
That adversary is going to have an
给定信息，猜测不同的随机标签，攻击者将有一个
advantage against the mac that's basically
one over two to the ten which is one over
对这个MAC的优势就是1除以2的10次方
a thousand twenty four and that's
definitely non negligible. So the adversary
即1024分之一，当然不是可忽略的
basically will successfully forge the mac
on a given message with probability one
那么攻击者会成功地为给定的信息伪造MAC
on a thousand which is insecure. However
it turns out this is the only example that
以千分之一的概率，这是不安全的，但事实上这是唯一的会有错误的例子
where things can go wrong, only when the
output of the function is small can things
仅当函数输出太小，事情才会有问题
go wrong. If the output of the PRF is
large Then we get a secure MAC out of this
如果这个PRF的输出很大，我们就可以获得一个这个函数的安全的MAC
function. And let's state the security
theorem here. So suppose we have a
我们看一个安全性定理。假设我们有
function 'F' that takes messages in 'X'
and outputs tags in 'Y', then the MAC
一个函数F，取X中的信息为输入，输出Y中的标签
that's derived from this PRF in fact is a
secure MAC. In particular, if you look at
那么由这个PRF推出的MAC事实上是安全的。特别地
the security theorem here, you'll see very
clearly the era bounds, in other words
如果大家看到这个安全性定理，会很清楚地看到这个误差上届，换句话说
since the PRF is secure we know that this
quantity here is negligible. And so if we
由于PRF是安全的，我们知道这个量是可忽略的
want this quantity to be negligible, this
is what we want, we want to say that no
如果我们希望这个量是可忽略的，这是我们想要的，我们想说
adversary can defeat the MAC 'I sub F',
that implies that we want this quantity to
没有攻击者可以击败MAC I_F，意味着我们希望这个量是可忽略的
be negligible, in other words we want the
output space to be large. And so for
换句话说，我们希望输出空间很大
example, taking a PRF that outputs eighty
bits is perfectly fine. That will generate
例如，取一个PRF，输出80位就很好了
an eighty bit MAC and therefore the
advantage of any adversary will be at most
它们会产生80位MAC，因此任意攻击者的优势
one over two to the eighty. So now the proof
of this theorem is really simple, so lets
最多是1除以2的80次方。那么这个定理的证明很简单
just go ahead and do it. So in fact lets
start by saying that suppose instead of a
我们来看看，事实上我们不从PRF开始
PRF we have a truly random function from
the message space to the tag space so this
假设我们有一个从信息空间到标签空间的真随机函数
is just a random function from X to Y
that's chosen at random from the set of
这是一个从X到Y的真随机函数，它是从所有函数集中随机选择的
all such functions. Now lets see if that
function can give us a secure mac. So what
我们看这个函数能否给我们一个安全的MAC
the adversary says is, 'I want a tag on
the message M1'. What he gets back is the
那么攻击者说，我想要信息M1的标签
tag which just happens to be the function
evaluated at the point M1. Notice there is
他获得了标签，即在点M1处的函数值
no key here because F is just a truly
random function from X to Y. And then the
注意这里没有密钥，因为F只是一个从X到Y的真随机函数
adversary gets to choose a message from M2
and he obtains the tag from M2, he choose
然后攻击者从选择信息M2，他获得了M2的标签
M3, M4 up to MQ and he obtains all the
corresponding tags. Now his goal is to
他选择M3，M4直到Mq，他获得了所有对应的标签
produce a message tag pair and we say that
he wins, remember that this is an
现在他的目标是产生一个信息标签对，也就是说他赢了，记得那就是
existential forgery, in other words first
of all T has to be equal to F of M This
存在性伪造，换句话说，首先一定有T=F(M)
means that 'T' is a valid tag for the
message 'M'. And second of all, the
这意味着T是M的一个有效标签。其次
message 'M' has to be new. So the message
'M' had better not be one of M-one to M-Q.
信息M必须是新的，信息M不能是M1到Mq中的任何一个
But let's just think about this for a
minute, what does this mean? So the
那我们想一想这是什么意思
adversary got to see the value of a truly
random function at the points M-one to M-Q
攻击者看到在点M1到Mq处这个真随机函数的值
and now he?s suppose to predict the value
of this function as some new point, M
现在他要预测新点M的函数值
However, for a truly random function, the
value of the function at the point M is
但是对于真随机函数，在点M的函数值
independent of its value at the points M-1
to M-Q. So the best the adversary can do
是独立的，所以攻击者能做的最好的
at predicting the value of the function at
the point M is just guess the value,
预测点M的函数值，就是猜
because he has no information about F of
M. And as a result his advantage if he
因为他没有任何函数F在M值的信息，因此他的优势
guesses the value of the function at the
point M he'll guess it right with
如果他猜在点M处的函数值，他猜中的概率
probability exactly one over Y. And then
the tag that he produced will be correct
是1除以|Y|。然后他产生的标签以概率1除以|Y|
with probability exactly one over Y. Okay,
again he had no information about the
是正确的。好，攻击者没有任何信息
value of the function of M and so the best
he could do is guess. And if he guesses,
是关于函数在M的值，最好的办法就是猜
he'll get it right with probability one
over Y. And now of course, because the
猜的话，他以1除以|Y|的概率猜对。当然
function capital F is a pseudo random
function The adversary is gonna behave the
因为函数F是随即函数，当我们
same whether we give him the truly random
function or the pseudo random function.
给攻击者真随机函数或伪随机函数 攻击者表现是一样的
The adversary can't tell the difference
and as a result even if we use a pseudo
攻击者不能说出它们的区别 因此，即使我们有一个
random function, the adversary is gonna
have advantages at most one over Y in
伪随机函数，攻击者在游戏中获胜的优势最多为1除以|Y|
winning the game. Okay, so you can see
exactly the security theorem, let's go
好，那么大家可以看到这个安全性定理
back there for just a second. Essentially
this is basically why we got an error term
我们回头看一会。这是我们为什么有这一误差项
of one over Y because of the guessing
attack and that's the only way that the
1除以|Y|，因为是猜测攻击所致，而且这是攻击者赢得游戏唯一的办法
attacker can win the game. So now that we
know that any secure PRF is also a secure
那么我们现在知道任何PRF
MAC, we already know that we have our
first example MAC. In particular, we know
同时也是安全的MAC，我们已经知道第一种MAC的例子。特别的
that AES, or at least we believe that AES
is a secure PRF, therefore, AES since it
我们知道AES，或者我们至少相信AES是一个安全的PRF，因此
takes sixteen byte inputs, right the
message space for AES is 128 bits, which
由于AES取16字节的输入，AES的信息空间是128位
is sixteen bytes. Therefore the AES cipher
essentially gives us a MAC that can match
即16字节。因此AES加密会给我们一个MAC
messages that are exactly sixteen bytes.
Okay, so that's our first example of a
匹配严格的16字节信息。好的，这是第一个MAC例子
MAC. But now the question is if we have a
PRF for small inputs like AES that only
现在问题是，如果我们有了一个PRF针对像AES这样的仅16字节的小输入
acts on sixteen bytes, can we build a MAC
for big messages that can act on gigabytes
那么我们能不能为长信息也构建一个MAC呢 比如几个G的数据呢？
of data? Sometimes I call this the
McDonald's problem. Basically given a
有时我们把这个称之为麦当劳问题
small MAC and we build a big MAC out of
it. In other words, given a MAC for small
给一个小的MAC，我们构建一个大MAC 换句话说，给定短信息的MAC
messages and we build a MAC for large
messages. So we're gonna look at two
我们构建长的MAC。我们看两个这样的机制
constructions for doing so. The first
example is called a CBC MAC that again
第一个例子叫做CBC MAC
takes PRF for small messages as input
and produces a PRF for very large
取针对短信息的PRF为输入 输出一个PRF，可以处理长信息
messages. As outputs. The second one we'll
see is HMAC which does the same thing
作为输出。第二个我们要看到的机制是HMAC 它做的事情是一样的
again takes a PRF for small inputs and
generates a PRF for very large inputs. Now
取处理短输入的PRF，产生能处理长输入的PRF
the two are used in very different
contexts. Cbc-mac is actually very
现在这两个被用在了不同的上下文中
commonly used in the banking industry. For
example, there's a system called the
CBC-MAC在银行业广为应用 例如有一个系统的叫做
Automatic Clearing House, ACH, which banks
use to clear checks with one another and
自动打扫房间ACH，银行使用这个系统来处理银行之间的支票
that system, CBC-MAC, is used to ensure
integrity of the checks as they're
CBC-MAC被用来确保支票的完整性
transferred from bank to bank. On the
Internet, protocols like SSL and IPsec and
支票是在银行之间传递的。在因特网上SSL、IPsec和SSH等协议
SSH, those all use HMAC for integrity. Two
different MACs and were gonna discuss them
都使用HMAC来保护完整性。这两个不同的MAC
in the next couple of segments. And as I
said were also gonna start from a PRF for
我们将在下面几节中讨论它们 如我所说，从处理短信息的PRF出发
small messages and produce PRF for
messages that are gigabytes long and in
产生能够的处理几个G的信息的PRF
particular they can both be substantiated
with AES as the underlying cipher. So the
特别地，它们两种MAC都可以用AES作为底层密码
last comment I want to make about these
PRF based MACs is that in fact their
那么我最后想说的是，关于这些基于PRF的MAC的
output can be truncated. So suppose we
have a PRF that outputs N bit outputs. So
事实上它们的输出是可以被截断的 假设我们有一个PRF，输出N位
again for AES this would be a PRF that
outputs 128 bits as outputs. Its an easy
对于AES，这是一个输出128位的PRF
lemma to show that in fact if you have an
N bit PRF if you truncated, in other words
这是一个容易证明的引理。事实上如果你有一个N位的PRF，如果你截断之，换句话说
if you only output first key bits The
result is also a secure PRF and the
如果你只输出前K位，结果依然是安全的PRF
intuition here is if the big PRF outputs N
bits of randomness for any inputs that you
直观地说，如果大PRF对任意输入，都能输出N位随机字符串
give to the PRF then certainly chopping it
off and truncating it to T bits is still
那么把结果截断成T位后
gonna look random. The attacker now gets
less information so his job of
看上去依然是随机的。攻击者获得更少的信息
distinguishing the outputs from random
just became harder. In other words, if the
所以他区分随机输出的工作会更困难。换句话说
N bit PRF is secure, then the T less than
N bit PRF, the truncated PRF, would also
如果N位PRF是安全的，那么T位PRF，截断PRF
be secure. So this is an easy lemma and
since any secure PRF also gives us a
也是安全的。这是一个神奇的引理，由于任何安全PRF
secure MAC, what this means is if you give
me a MAC that's based on a PRF and what I
也能给我们一个安全的MAC，这意味着如果你给我一个基于PRF的MAC
can do is I can truncate it to W bits,
however, because of the error term in the
我可以把它截断成N位，但是，因为基于PRF的MAC的定理中的误差项
MAC based PRF theorem we know that
truncating to W bits will only be secure
我们知道截断到W位是安全的
as long as one over two to the W is
negligible. So if you truncate the PRF to
只要1除以2的|W|次方是可忽略的 那么你如果截断PRF到只有3位
only three bits, the resulting MAC is not
going to be secure. However, if you
那么得到的MAC就是不安全的。不过
truncate it to say 80 bits or maybe even
64 bits, then the resulting MAC is still
如果你把它截断成80位，甚至是64位 那么得到的MAC也是
gonna be a secure MAC. Okay, so the thing
to remember here is that even though we
一个安全的MAC。好，需要记住的事情是
use AES to construct larger PRFs and the
output of these PRFs is gonna be 128 bits,
即使我们使用AES来构建更大的PRF 最后PRF的输出将是128位
it doesn't mean that the MAC itself has to
produce 128 bit tags We can always
这并不意味着MAC自身必须产生128位标签
truncate the outputs to 90 bits or 80
bits, and as a result, we would get still
我们总可以吧结果截断成90位或80位 因此，我们依然可以得到
secure MACs but now the output tag is
gonna be more reasonable size and doesn't
安全的MAC，但现在输出标签有着更合理的大小
have to be the full 128 bits. Okay, so in
the next segment we're gonna look at how
不必是满满的128位。好，在下一节中我们将看CBC-MAC是如何工作的
the CBC-MAC works.